And what this kind of led me to
realise, and this is very strongly
connected with the
business of getting stuck,
is that when you do something new,
when you do something different,
you experience a bunch of emotions.
And they may not all be positive
emotions. In fact, a lot
of them might be negative.
And what you've done by giving
yourself some negative emotions, which
then you have to deal with, and you
probably don't have to, you probably
have to deal with them in a way other.
than just avoiding the thing that
generated the negative emotions.
Because if you do that, if you avoid
the thing that generated the negative
emotions, then you'll just give
up. And, you know, that's fitting
for tonight, really, isn't it? You
know, I've got nobody. And like, you
know, I could pretend I'm not upset
about it, but I am a little bit upset
about it. But if I just give up,
because this happened, then kind
of I've given up. I've given myself
some work of having a bunch of emotions
and I've given up as a result of
it.
So this is kind of like a really
important aspect. So like very often
when people talk about persevering
with things, they talk about like
carrying on doing hard work, etc.
Very rarely do they talk about kind
of like dealing with the negative
emotions and kind of getting past
those negative emotions. And that I
think is one of the most important
aspects of not giving up.
So it's emotional work. You've
given yourself some emotional work,
then you have to do it.